난 우주에서 태어났다
I was born in space.
내 얼굴에 비치는 햇살을
느껴본 적이 없었다
I've never felt the sun on my face
진짜 공기를 숨쉬거나
물 위에 떠본 적도 없었다
or breathed real air,
or floated in the water.
우리들 중 아무도
None of us have.
3세대 동안 Ark가
인류를 지켜줬지만
For 3 generations,
The Ark has kept what's
left of the human race alive,
지금은 죽어가고 있다
but now our home is dying, and we
우린 인류의 마지막 희망이다
are the last hope of mankind.
100 prisoners sent on a
desperate mission to the ground.
100명의 재소자들은 극단적인 임무로
지구로 보내졌다
개개인들은 법을 어겼기에
이곳에 왔다
Each of us is here
because we broke the law.
지구에선
법이 존재하지 않는다
On the ground, there is no law.
우리가 할 일은
살아남으면서
All we have to do is survive.
지구의 시험대에
오를 것이다
But we will be tested,
by the Earth, by the secrets it hides,
그리고 무엇보다도
서로의 비밀을 감추면서
and most of all, by each other.
The 100 지난 이야기
Man, voice-over: Previously on "The 100"...
재소자 319, 벽을 향해
Man: Prisoner 319, take off the watch.
제 아빠 꺼예요
No. It was my father's.
- 엄마?
- 널 지구로 보내는 거야
- Mom?
- You're being sent to the ground.
클라크, 네 아빠를
체포해서 미안해
Clarke, I'm sorry I got
your father arrested.
아빠는 체포된 게
아니라, 웰스
They didn't arrest my father, Wells.
처형 당했어
They executed him.
아톰, 내 여동생 이 캠프에서
못 떠나게 해
Atom, my sister doesn't leave this camp.
누가 내 동생을 건들면
보복이 있을 거야
Anyone who touches her, they answer to me.
아톰
Bellamy: Atom.
제스퍼가 공격 당했어
그들이 끌고 갔어
Clarke: Jasper was hit. They took him.
살아 있어
Clarke: He's alive.
[Crowd cheering, announcer
speaking indistinctly on TV]
1년 전
_
돌파한다
Man: There we go. There we go.
느껴져?
Feel that? Feel that?
봤지?
See that?
곧 운동량에
변화가 온다고
Here comes the momentum change.
수비
Defense.
거기 수비
The defense is there.
- 공 올려, 그거야!
- 이런!
- Serve it up.
- Yeah! Oh!
- 그거야!
- 바로 거기
- Yeah! Ho!
- Man: Right here, kid.
- 무적이구만
- 완패는 각오해
- They're unbeatable.
- Prepare for crushing defeat.
아직 끝난 건 아냐
It's not over yet.
사실 147년 전에
끝났어
Actually, it was over 147 years ago.
상세하잖아
A technicality.
포기해
자네는 질 거야
Give it up. You're going down.
내가 뭘 놓쳤나요?
What'd I miss?
당신 남편과 딸이
불쾌하게 해
Your husband and daughter being obnoxious.
착하게들 노세요
Better play nice.
어서 한 골 넣어야지
Wells: Come on, get down the field, fire.
시간 낭비야
시간...자기
Waste of time. Waste... hey, baby.
안녕
Hi.
클리닉을 막 떠날 때
베넷을 만났고
So, I ran into Bennett when
I was leaving the clinic
당신이 부탁한 그 시스템
분석을 가지고 있대
and he has that systems
analysis that you asked for.
Ho-ho-ho-ho!
This isn't gonna last.
- 오래가지 않을 거야
- 운동량에 대한 거였지?
Wells: What was that about momentum?
나도 운동량이 느껴져
Oh, oh, I feel the momentum.
알았어
Ok.
지금 갈려고?
What? You're going now?
몇 분이면 돼
Just for a few minutes.
괜찮아?
Everything ok?
그럼, 이 오래된 정거장은
늘 뭔가가 있잖아
Oh, yeah. You know this old boat.
It's always something.
[Moaning]
맥박이 380이야
His pulse is 380.
[Moaning]
잠이나 자!
Man: Go back to sleep!
조용해!
Second man: Quiet!
쟤들 말 듣지마
Don't listen to them.
넌 잘 이겨낼 거야, 응?
You're gonna make it through this, ok?
약속해
[Moaning] Promise.
벌써 죽은 게 아니였어?
Man: Can he just die already?
깨끗한 물 좀 가져올게
I'm gonna get clean water.
잘 지켜 봐
Keep an eye on him.
[Jasper moaning]
[Man moaning]
안 돼!
Child: No!
Child: No! No!
일어나 봐, 괜찮아
괜찮아
Hey, wake up. It's ok. It's ok.
그냥 꿈이야
It's just a dream.
너 샤를로트지, 응?
You're Charlotte, right?
난 클라크야
I'm Clarke.
무서운 게
당연해
It's ok to be scared.
얘기하고 싶니?
Do you want to talk about it?
제...부모님이었어요
It's... my parents.
우주로 처형되면서...
They were floated and they...
신령스러운 꿈이여서
난...
and they seeded my
dreams and I just...
난 이해해
I understand.
내 아빠도 우주로
처형됐어
My dad was floated, too.
여긴 어떻게 해서
온 거니?
So, how did you end up here?
우린 재분배 센터에
부모님 물건을 가지고 가다...
Well... we were taking my parents' things
to the redistribution center and...
잃어버렸어요
I kind of lost it.
제가 간수를 공격했대요
They said I assaulted a guard.
네 자신을 탓할 순 없잖아
I can't say I blame you.
저기 위 빛나는 별
보이지?
See that bright star up there?
우리 머리 위를
선회하는 Ark야
That's the Ark orbiting above us.
저곳에 무슨 일이
일어났던
I think whatever happened up there,
그 고통은...
you know, the pain...
지금은 극복할 수 있을 거야
maybe we can move past that now.
어쩌면 지구에 있는 게
두 번째 기회인 셈이지
Maybe being on the ground
is our second chance.
그걸 정말 믿어요?
Do you really believe that?
그럴려고
I'm trying to.
이 길은 북쪽이야
서둘러
I think this is north. Come on.
그래? 방금 저 길로 와서
내가 별 보며 길 안내할 수 있는데
Really? Because we just came from that way,
miss I-can-navigate-with-the-stars.
이틀간 길 잃은 건
네 잘못이야
It's your fault we've
been lost for two days.
우린 절대 도망치지
말았어야 했어
Never should've gone off by ourselves.
이리 와, 내일이면
드랍십을 찾을 거야
Come on. We'll find the dropship tomorrow.
어젯밤에도 그 말 했잖아
그리고 나 배고파
That's what you said last
night. And I'm hungry.
트리나, 진정해
우린 괜찮아
Trina, relax. We're fine.
저게 느껴져?
Did you feel that?
저게 뭐야?
What is that?
몰라
I don't know.
볼 수가 없어!
Oh! I can't see!
여길 빠져나가야 해
Let's get out of here.
맙소사, 몸이 타!
Oh, my God, it burns! Aah!
Aah!
[Both screaming]
[Jasper moaning]
그 새낀 항상
내 일에 참견해
That damn kid, always messing with my head.
그리 볼 날도
얼마 안 남았어
He's not gonna last much longer.
새로운 핑계거리를
짜내라고
Better think of a new excuse.
일은 그렇게 하는 거야
That's how it's done.
약 0.8km 사방팔방
수색했는데
We searched a half-mile all directions.
트리나 혹은 파스칼의
흔적은 없어
No sign of Trina or Pascal.
그곳에 갔었을 때
특이한 나무 봤어?
Visit your special tree
when you were out there?
아톰은 벌 받은 거야
내버려 둬
Atom took his punishment. Let it go.
지면인일 수도 있어
Could be grounders.
맞아, 아님 공설 울타리에
있었을 수도...
Yeah, or they could be in pound town.
요즘 이곳 주위로
들끓잖아
Lot of that going around recently.
[Jasper moaning]
저기, 벨라미
얘들이 무서워 해
Look, Bellamy, people are scared,
그리고 저기 죽어가는 애
and that dying kid,
이곳 사기에
별 도움이 안 돼
he's not helping the morale around here.
내가 음식을 더 찾으면
사기는 왕성해질 거야
Morale will go up when
I find them more food.
트리나와 파스칼에 대해
물어보면 뭐라고 해?
And what do we say when they
ask about Trina and Pascal?
지금? 별거 아냐
길 잃을 수도 있잖아
Now? Nothing. It's
possible they're just lost.
이따 사냥하러 갈 때
주변을 경계해야지
We'll keep an eye out for
them when we go hunting later.
뭐라도 죽이러 가자고
Let's go kill something.
넌 오지마
You're not going.
여기에 있어
I need you to stay here.
지면인들이 에워싸면
If the grounders are circling,
보호자 없이
이곳을 떠날 순 없어
we can't leave this place unprotected.
좋아, 누군가는 고글 보이에게
입닥치게 해야지
Fine. Somebody better tell
goggle boy to keep it shut.
지면인들이 상처에
뜸을 떴어
The grounders cauterized
the wound. Saved his life.
쟤 목숨을 살려준 거야
미끼 유인으로
산채로 매달은 것일 수도 있어
Saved his life so they could
string him up for live bait.
이곳은 에덴 동산이 아냐
Garden of eden this ain't.
감염이 돼서
곪을 수도 있겠어
This is infected. He could be septic.
팔찌로 Ark에 연락할
진척은 있어?
Any progress on using the wristbands
to contact the Ark?
몬티?
Monty?
확실히 안 될 거야
That would be a firm no.
- 엄만 어떻게 하는지 알 텐데
- 좀 어때?
My mother would know what to do.
How's he doing?
- 어떨 것 같아, 웰스?
- 난 도우려는 거야
How does it look like he's doing, Wells?
Hey, I'm just trying to help.
[Jasper moaning]
좋아, 돕고 싶어?
Right. You want to help?
꽉 붙잡아
Hold him down.
나 이 방법 안 좋아하는데?
I'm not gonna like this, am I?
[Jasper moaning]
저기
Hey.
나 정말로 쉬고 싶어
I could really use a break from this place.
너랑 나랑 나비원에
여행하는 건 어때?
What do you say you and me
take a trip to the butterfly field?
응?
Huh?
내가 너무 예민해서?
Am I being too subtle?
[Scraping]
아톰
Atom. [Continues scraping]
- 무기로...
- 아톰에게 뭐라 했어?
- Man: With weapons...
- What did you do to Atom?
아톰은 괜찮아
Atom's fine.
그럼 왜 날 씹는데?
Then why did he blow me off?
흥미가 없었나 보지
Maybe he's just not interested.
오빤 모두를 내게서
떨어뜨려 놓잖아
You can't keep everyone away from me.
아톰이 깨달은 거야
Atom had to learn.
내게 복종하고
대가를 치러야지
You disobey me, you pay the price.
걔는 대가를 치렀으니
이젠 괜찮아
He paid the price. Now we're good.
지금 내가 대가를
치를 테니
Now I'm paying the price.
다음엔 오빠가 계속
권력을 휘두르고 싶으면
So, next time you decide
to go on, a power trip,
난 제외시켜줘
leave me out of it.
Jasper: Aah!
[Screaming]
계속 붙잡아
Hold him still.
감염된 부위를
잘라내야 해
I need to cut away the infected flesh.
그만해!
그러다 죽겠어
Stop it! You're killing him.
살릴려는 거야
She's trying to save his life.
못 살려
She can't.
물러서
Back off.
죽게 놔두려 했으면
수마일을 끌고 오지도 않았어
We didn't drag him through miles of woods
just to let him die.
가망이 없어
Kid's a goner.
네가 그걸 볼 수 없으면
망상에 빠진 거야
If you can't see that, you're deluded.
쟤 때문에 사람들이
미치가고 있어
He's making people crazy.
제스퍼가 너희들에게
불편하다면 미안해
Sorry if Jasper's an inconvenience to you,
하지만 여긴 Ark가 아냐
but this isn't the Ark.
여기에선
모든 생명이 중요해
Down here, every life matters.
쟤를 함 봐
쓸모없는 인간이야
Take a look at him. He's a lost cause.
옥타비아, 난 엄마가 사람들을
고치는 걸 평생 봐왔어
Octavia, I've spent my whole life
watching my mother heal people.
내가 희망이 있다고 하면
희망이 있는 거야
If I say there's hope, there's hope.
희망에 대한 게 아니라
배짱에 대한 거야
This isn't about hope, it's about guts.
힘든 선택에 배짱이 없어도 돼
내가 해
You don't have the guts to
make the hard choices. I do.
쟨 3일간 저러고 있었어
He's been like this for 3 days.
내일까지 안 좋아지면
내가 직접 죽일 테야
If he's not better by tomorrow,
I'll kill him myself.
옥타비아, 가자
Octavia, let's go.
난 여기 있을래
I'm staying here.
권력을 갈망하는
이기주의자 새끼
Power-hungry, self-serving jackass.
자신 말고는
다른 사람은 신경도 안 써
He doesn't care about anyone but himself.
악의는 없어
No offense.
맞아, 벨라미는 끝내주잖아
Yeah. Bellamy is all that.
한편으론 옳기도 하고
But he also happens to be right.
[Door closes]
어떻게 됐어?
How'd it go?
여보
Hey.
결정적이라고
자하에게 말했어
Well, I told Jaha it's definitive.
Ark엔 1년치 산소가 남았어
어쩌면 2년치
The Ark's got a year of
oxygen left, maybe two.
당신이 고칠 거잖아
You'll fix it.
이번엔 안 돼
Not this time.
해봤는데, 애비
작은 결함이 아냐
I've tried, Abby. This isn't a glitch.
시스템 고장이야
It's a system failure.
사람들은 알아야 해
People need to know.
안 돼
패닉에 빠질 거야
No. They'll panic.
- 케인처럼 말하네
- 그의 말이 옳으니깐
You sound like Kane.
Because he's right.
아니, 진실을 회피할 순 없어
No. We can't avoid the truth.
모두가 Ark의 해결책을 찾는 데
마음을 쏟아야 해
We have to let everyone on the Ark
put their minds to a solution.
위험한 무정부 상태로?
What, and risk anarchy?
아니, 너무 위험해
No. It's too dangerous.
의회의 '함구하라는' 명령에
따른다고 약속해
Promise me that you'll
obey the council's orders,
that you'll keep it quiet.
약속해
Promise me.
난 못해
I can't.
클라크를 위해서라도 해
For Clarke. Do it for Clarke.
이건 클라크를
위해서라도 할 거야
I am doing this for Clarke.
당신을 우주로
날려보낼 거야, 제이크
They'll float you, Jake.
당신이 하겠다면
난 막을 수 없어
If you do this, I won't be able to stop it.
화났구나
You're mad.
화 안 났어
I'm not mad.
너도 제스퍼가 쓸모없다면
계속 그래
You want to think Jasper's
a lost cause, go ahead.
- 네가 틀렸어
- 난 그랬으면 해
- You're wrong.
- I hope I am.
이게 뭐든 간에
항생성분이 있어야 돼
Whatever this stuff is, it has to have had
antibiotic properties.
내가 함 볼게
Let me take a look.
내 도움을 거절하기 전에
Before you refuse my help, remember
누가 지구의 식물학에
능통한지 기억해
who aced botany in Earth skills.
지면인들이 찜질약으로
사용한 거야
The grounders used it as a poultice.
어쩌면 TEA이 좀 더
효과적일 지도 몰라
TEA : 테트라에틸암모늄
I'm thinking a tea might
be even more effective
뭔지를 알아낼 수만
있다면
if we can figure out what it is.
난 이게 뭔지 알아
해초야
I know what it is. Seaweed.
봐...뿌리 조직이 없어
Look... no root structure.
좋아, 그럼 근처에
해수가 있을 거야
Right. Well, then there must
be a water source nearby.
응, 물의 흐름이 느려야 하고
바위가 많아야 해
Yeah, it would have to have
a slow current, lots of rocks.
물색깔은 녹색보단
붉은색에 가까울 거야
The water would probably be
more red than green.
마침 그곳을 알아
I know just the place.
좋아, 가자
All right. Let's go.
야, 난 이게 어떻게
생겼는지 아는데, 너희는?
Hey. I know what this
stuff looks like. Do you?
You know, you should, uh,
이곳 전체가 날 싫어하는 걸
네가 재고했으면 해
really rethink this whole hating me thing.
지면인들이 아니라
It's not just the grounders.
우린 범죄자들로
둘러싸여 있잖아
We're surrounded by criminals.
우린 서로가 필요해
We need each other.
우린 다시 친구가 되어야 해
We're gonna be friends again.
넌 내 아빠를 죽였어
그럴 가능성은 없어
You got my dad killed. Not possible.
이곳은 지구야, 클라크
뭐든지 가능해
This is Earth, Clarke. Anything's possible.
- 내버려 둬
- 그러지
I'd let it go.
Yeah.
난 클라크를 너보단
훨씬 이전부터 알아왔어
Well, I've known Clarke her whole life
better than you ever will, so,
내버려 둘진
내가 결정해
I'll decide when to let it go.
둘이 친한 것 쯤은
알아
Yeah, I can tell you guys are close.
[Bang]
[Bang bang]
뭔데?
What is it?
Uhh.
하! 자동차야
Ha! It's an automobile.
서둘러, 이건 100년간
이곳에 있었어
Come on, guys. This
thing's been here 100 years.
그렇지? 기다릴 순 있잖아
제스퍼는 아냐
All right? It can wait.
Jasper can't.
[Oinking]
쉬-쉬-쉬
내 꺼야
Shh-shh-shh-shh. She's mine.
[Crack]
잡아
Man: Get him.
넌 대체 누구야?
Who the hell are you?
샤를로트예요
Charlotte.
널 죽일 뻔 했어
I almost killed you.
왜 캠프로 안 가니?
Why aren't you back at camp?
죽어가는 오빠가
옆에 있어서
Well, what with that guy who was dying,
더이상...
듣고 싶지 않았어요
I just... I couldn't listen anymore.
여긴 지면인들이 있어
There's grounders out here.
꼬마 숙녀에겐
너무 위험해
It's too dangerous for a little girl.
난 꼬마 아니에요
I'm not little.
좋아, 근데...
Ok, then...
무기 없이는
사냥할 순 없잖아
But you can't hunt without a weapon.
전에 죽인 적은 있어?
Ever killed something before?
누가 알아?
그 방면에 소질이 있을지
Who knows? Maybe you're good at it.
근데, 해초가 어떻게 생겼어?
So, what does this seaweed look like?
[Sigh]
저렇게
Like that.
저게 옥타비아를 물었잖아
얼마나 컸어?
Hey, that thing that bit Octavia,
how big was it?
엄청나게
Big. We could rig this
이걸 풀어서
그물을 만들 수 있을 거야
into some kind of a net.
물속으로 가라앉힐 것을
찾아봐야지
Find something to lower it into the water.
아님 그냥 가져오던가
Or we could just do that.
[Birds squawking]
여길 벗어나자고
Man: Let's get out of here.
[Bellow]
지면인들?
Grounders?
- 함성일 수도 있어
- 아님 경고던가
It could be a war cry
or a warning.
저건 대체 뭐야?
Finn: What the hell is that?
달려
달려!
Run. Run!
클라크
Clarke.
네 차례야
You're up.
- 클라크
- 미안
Clarke.
Sorry.
네 전략은 패배하기에
빠른 지름길이면
Well, if your strategy
is to lose really fast,
멋진 한수였어
that was a great move.
왜 그래?
What's going on?
별거 아냐
Nothing.
내게 털어놔
You can talk to me.
아빠가 산소 시스템에
문제점을 발견했는데
My dad found a problem
with the oxygen system.
알면 안 되는 일이였어
I'm not supposed to know.
작동하지 않는 게
있더라도
They've had other malfunctions.
항상 대처방안을
모색하잖아
They always figure out
a way to deal with it.
아니, 못 고칠 수도 있어
No. This one might not be fixable.
의회는 아무도 모르길 원해
The council doesn't want anyone to know.
의회의 의미가
내 아빠?
The council meaning my dad?
응, 엄마와
다른 의원들도
Yeah. And my mom and the others.
아빠가 대중에
공개할 거야
I think he's gonna go public anyway.
클라크, 안 돼
Clarke, he can't. He'll get floated.
- 네 아빠 처형 당할 거야
- 알아
I know.
근데 아빠 말이 옳다면?
But what if he's right?
사람들은 진실을
알 자격이 없는 거야?
Don't people deserve to know the truth?
내가 말한 걸
네 아빠에게 말하지 마
You can't tell your dad I told you.
아무에게도
You can't tell anyone.
네 비밀은 지켜줄게
Your secret's safe with me.
약속해
I promise.
클라크, 달려!
[Bellow] Clarke, run!
[Bellow] [Coughing]
[Bellow]
안으로 들어올 거야
It's getting inside.
구멍들을 막아
Finn: Seal any openings.
[Coughing]
[Bellow]
서둘러!
이쪽으로 동굴이 있어
Come on! There are caves this way.
[Bellow]
벨라미!
Man: Bellamy!
[Coughing] Bellamy!
[Coughing]
- 무슨 일이야?
- 공기가 자욱해서
- What's going on?
- Air got thick,
피부가 타들어가고 있어
everybody's skin started burning.
몬티, 오빠가 밖에 있어
Monty, my brother's out there.
괜찮을 거야
우리 모두 괜찮을 거야
He'll be fine. We'll all be fine.
여전히 그 상태야
Man: It's still out there.
필사적으로
도망쳤어야 했어
Clarke: Look, we should
just make a run for it.
제스퍼는 더이상
시간이 없어
Jasper can't wait much longer.
황산 안개에 우리가 죽으면
제스퍼도 끝장이야
Us dying in a cloud of acid fog
isn't gonna help Jasper.
- 그거...
- 술이야
- Is that...
- Booze.
밀주, 싸구려 술
Hooch. Rotgut.
조심해, 핀
잘못 될...
Well, careful. Finn, it could be...
위스키네
Whiskey, I think.
아르고 역에
밀주보단 낫네
Better than the moonshine on agro station.
알콜은 독성이 있어
Alcohol's toxic.
여긴 지구야
모든 게 독성이야
This is Earth. Everything's toxic.
게다가 예로부터
통과 의례야
Plus, it's a time-honored rite of passage.
우린 통과할 거야
We'll pass.
나도 전통을 방해할 마음은
추호도 없어
Far be it from me to stand
in the way of tradition.
[Coughs]
[Clarke sighs]
안 돼!
No!
샤를로트, 일어나
Charlotte, wake up.
미안해요
I'm sorry.
자주 이러니?
Does it happen often?
[Sigh]
뭐가 무서운데?
What are you scared of?
있잖아, 문제 될 건 없어
You know what? It doesn't matter.
중요한 것은
네가 뭘 할 수 있느냐는 거지
The only thing that matters is
what you do about it.
근데...저 졸려요
But... I'm asleep.
공포는 공포야
Fears are fears.
네가 깨어날 때
악령들을 죽이면
Slay your demons when you're awake,
네가 잠 잘 때
나타나지 않을 거야
they won't be there to
get you when you sleep.
네, 근데...
어떻게요?
Yeah, but... How?
넌 약해질 여력이 없어
You can't afford to be weak.
여기선 약한 게 죽음이야
공포도 죽음이고
Down here, weakness is
death, fear is death.
내가 준 칼 함 보자
Let me see that knife I gave you.
자, 네가 두렵다고 느낄 때
Now, when you feel afraid,
그 칼을 꽉 잡고
you hold tight to that knife
말해 '엿 먹어'
and you say, "screw you."
'난 무섭지 않아'
"I'm not afraid."
엿 먹어
난 무섭지 않아
Screw you. I'm not afraid.
엿 먹어
난 무섭지 않아
Screw you. I'm not afraid.
네 악령들을 죽여
Slay your demons, kid.
그럼 푹 잘 수 있을 테니
Then you'll be able to sleep.
몇 시간 지났어
제스퍼는...
It's been hours. Jasper...
잘 보호받고 있어
Is in good hands.
옥타비아가 잘 돌볼 거야
Octavia will take care of him.
말이 나온 김에
While we're on the subject,
왜 모두들 내가 제스퍼를
안 죽었으면 하는 게
why is it that everyone
thinks me wanting Jasper
to not die is a bad thing?
나쁜 일이라 생각하지?
내가 우울한 사람이니
재미있을 수 있잖아
Like I'm such a downer. I can be fun.
그래, 너도 내가 재밌지?
그렇지?
Yeah. You think I'm fun. Right?
응, 여러 가지로
Oh, yeah. Among other things.
넌 재밌어
You're fun.
넌 그때를 기억...
You remember that time...
네가 날 배신한 그때와
아빠가 처형된 게 기억나냐고?
Remember that time you betrayed me
and got my father executed?
그래, 기억나
Yeah, I remember.
우린 어딨었지? 재밌어
Where were we? Fun.
Yeah.
네가 그 말을 했을 때부터
난 말 안 했어
Well, since you brought it up,
and I didn't, because
꺼내고 싶지 않았으니깐
I don't want to talk about it,
넌 무슨 생각을 했었는데?
what were you thinking?
내 실수였어, 클라크
I made a mistake, Clarke.
내 실수였어, 클라크?
"I made a mistake, Clarke."
그걸론 부족해
Not good enough.
근데 말야
You know, I bet
넌 네 아빠에게
달려갈 수 밖에 없었지
you couldn't wait to run to daddy.
아빠에게 다 얘기하면
Tell him everything
자기가 늘 원하던 완벽한
아들이라 믿을 테니깐
so that he'd finally believe
you were the perfect son he always wanted.
뭐라고 말해?
What do you want me to say?
난 해명해 주길 원해
I want an explanation.
해명할 수가 없어
I can't give you one.
난 아빠를 믿을 수 있다고
생각했어
I thought I could trust him.
하긴, 나도 내 절친을
믿을 수 있다고 생각했지
Well, I thought I could
trust my best friend.
우리 둘 다 잘못했어
Guess we were both wrong.
- 난 아직 네 친구야
- 아니야
I'm still your friend.
No, you're not. If you were my friend,
네가 내 친구라면
저 안개 속을 걸어나가
다시는 돌아오지 마
you would walk out into
that fog and never come back.
저기...우리 진정 좀
하는 게 어때?
Ok, how about we just... take it easy.
난 진정할 방법을 몰라
I have no idea how to do that.
[Sniffs]
그럼, 아직도 재미가 없어?
So, we having fun yet?
[Jasper moaning]
쟤 때문에 미치겠어
Girl: That kid's driving me crazy.
더이상 못 듣겠어
Boy: Can't take this much longer.
누가 쟤 입을 좀 틀어막아
Someone needs to shut that kid up.
[Jasper moaning]
시간 됐어
내가 끝내지
That's it. I'm ending this.
벨라미가 내일까지
시간을 준댔잖아
I heard Bellamy gave him till tomorrow.
맞아, 근데 벨라미는
여기에 없잖아?
Yeah, well, Bellamy isn't here, is he?
쟤는 죽어가고 있어
The kid's dying anyway.
난 일을 마무리 짓는 거야
I'm just getting it over with.
머피가 제스퍼를
죽이려고 해!
Murphy's going to kill Jasper!
다른 쪽에도 잠가
The lock's on the other side.
못 들어오게 해!
Don't let him in!
내가 죽여줄게, 응?
들여보내 줘!
I'm gonna kill him, ok? Let me in!
들여보내 줘, 몬티!
Let me in, Monty! Uhh!
서두르지 마
여긴 괜찮아
No rush. I'm fine here.
알았어!
I got it!
움직여!
Move it!
너희 둘 이 승강구 여는 게
좋을 거야!
Murphy: Both of you better
open up this hatch right now!
불확실한 이때에
Jake: In this time of uncertainty,
우린 시민으로써
뭉쳐야 합니다
we will come together as a people.
여러분들은 진실을 알아야 하기에
말씀드리는 겁니다
I'm telling you this because
you must know the truth
내 아이와 여러분 아이들의
미래를 위해서라도요
and because I want a future
for my child and yours.
강해져야 합니다
Be strong.
의회에 불복종하실려고요?
Clarke: You're gonna disobey the council?
아빠, 전 아빠와 엄마가
나눈 얘기 들었어요
Dad, I know. I heard you and mom.
너도 아는구나
Ok, you know.
아빤 오랫동안
이 문제를 생각해 왔다
I've been thinking about this a long time.
사람들도 알 권리가 있어
The people have a right to know.
- 네 엄마는 이해를 못하더구나
- 계획은 뭐예요?
Your mother doesn't understand.
What's the plan?
넌 알 필요 없단다
You don't need to know the plan.
비디오 영상을 만든 다음
뭐요?
You're making a video, so, what?
중앙 컴퓨터 통신실에
침입하실려고요?
You're gonna break into
the communications mainframe?
아빠 자신을 자멸하거나
정신 나간 소리를 하겠죠
Making you either suicidal
or incredibly dumb.
너 전형적인 10대처럼
행동하기 시작할
Wow. You are picking a fine moment
좋은 때를 골랐구나
to start behaving like a typical teenager.
- 제가 도울게요
- 안 돼
- I'm gonna help you.
- No.
안 돼, 클라크
그러면 안 돼
No, Clarke, you're not.
- 하지만 저도...
- 절대로 안 돼
- But I can...
- Absolutely not.
안 돼
안 돼, 아가
No. No, baby.
[Kiss]
네 엄마에게서
고집을 물려받았어
You get that stubborn streak
from your mother, you know.
그 중에서 난 너와
네 엄마를 사랑해
One of many things I
love about both of you.
제이크 그리핀
반역 혐의로 체포한다
Jake Griffin, you're
under arrest for treason.
아빠?
Dad? Dad?
안 돼요, 안 돼요
안 돼요...
No, no, no, no.
내 딸에게서 손 치워
Get your hands off of her.
날 놔줘요!
Let me go!
Ohh.
제가 경고할게요
방법을 찾아낼 게요
I'll warn them. I'll find a way.
클라크, 아빠 말 들어
그러지 마
No, Clarke, no, listen to
me. Do not... do not do that.
손 치워요!
날 놔줘요!
Get off of me! Let me go!
아빠!
Let me go! Dad! Dad!
안개가 걷혔어
서둘러
The fog's cleared. Come on.
가자, 제스퍼가 기다려
Let's go. Jasper's waiting.
어젯밤 꽤 격렬했어
Finn: Last night was pretty intense.
너와 클라크...
You and Clarke ever...
아니, 그런 건 아냐
No. Not like that.
그럼, 날 좀 도와줘
So, help me out.
네 절친이 뭔가 크게
터진다고 했는데
Your best friend tells you
something fairly explosive.
넌 혼자만 알고 싶어하는
타입으로 보이거든
You seem like the type of guy
that'd keep it to yourself.
넌 날 모르잖아
You don't know me.
왜 그런거야?
Why'd you do it?
몰라
왜 상관해?
I don't know. Why do you care?
넌 Ark의 규칙을
알고 있었어
You knew what the rules were on the Ark.
쟤 아빠가 처형당하는 걸
알고 있었잖아
You had to know her dad would get floated.
난 선택을 했어
I made a choice.
쟤가 남은 평생
날 증오한다면
If she hates me for the rest of my life,
난 옳은 선택을 한 거야
I made the right choice,
그러니 그 정도로만 알아둬
and that's all you have to know.
안개는 다 걷혔어
It's all clear.
누구 있어?
Anybody out here?
존스?
Jones?
여기야!
Jones: We're here!
너희를 놓쳐서 혼란스러웠는데
어디에 있었어?
Bellamy: Lost you in
the stew. Where'd you go?
아래쪽 동굴로 들어갔어
Made it to a cave down there.
- 그건 대체 뭐였어?
- 나도 몰라
The hell was that?
I don't know.
아톰은 어딨어?
유독성 안개 때문에
100년된 차에 갇히다니
Trapped in a 100-year-old car by toxic fog.
어젯밤은 꽤...
Whew. Last night was pretty...
뭐더라? 재밌었어
What's the word? Fun.
재미 없었어
무책임한 행동이었어
It wasn't fun. It was irresponsible.
안개가 두 번째 걷혔을 때
떠났어야 했어
We should've left the
second the fog cleared.
설령 안개가 걷혔어도
Even if the fog cleared,
밤에 이 숲을 헤쳐서
가진 못했을 거야
we'd never make it back
through these woods at night.
너 웰스에게
좀 까칠하던데
You were kind of rough on Wells.
그건 아냐
Hardly.
걔는 정말 정직한 애야
He's a pretty straight-up guy.
널 사랑하잖아
알고 있었지?
And he loves you. You know that, right?
매번 네 아빠에 대한
주제가 튀어 나오면
But every time your dad comes up,
네게 명확한 답변을
못하잖아
he won't give you a straight answer.
뭔가 숨기고 있다는
생각이 들어
Makes me think he's hiding something.
그래서 네게 물어볼 게 있어
So, I gotta ask you.
웰스가 네 아빠를 고발했다는데
무슨 근거로 확신해?
How sure are you that
Wells is the one who turned in your dad?
100%, 됐지?
100%. All right?
난 쟤에게만 말했어
He's the only one I told.
그걸 아는 게 쟤 뿐이야?
Is he the only one who knew?
Girl: Aah!
누구야?
Who was that?
Aah!
개자식
아톰
Son of a bitch. Atom.
날 죽여
Kill me. Kill me.
Kill me.
[Gasping]
[Atom coughing]
숨을 쉴 수가...
I... can't... breathe.
겁내지 마
Don't be afraid.
캠프로 돌아 가
Go back to camp.
샤를로트, 너도
Charlotte, you too.
날 죽여
Kill me.
벨라미, 제발
Bellamy, please.
[Atom coughs]
비명을 들었어
I heard screams.
샤를로트가 발견했어
Bellamy: Charlotte found him.
그 애를 캠프로 보냈어
I sent her back to camp.
알았어
Ok.
내가 도와줄게
알았지?
I'm gonna help you, all right?
[Humming]
[Indistinct chatter]
제스퍼에게 가야 돼
Clarke: We've gotta get to Jasper.
약을 제조하려면
끓인 물이 필요해
I'll need boiled water
to make the medicine.
클라크가 필요한 거
갖다 줘
Get Clarke whatever she needs.
난 무덤 파러 가는 게
낫겠어
I better go get this grave dug.
때가 지났어
제스퍼를 죽일 거야
It's about time. They're gonna kill Jasper.
약은 구했어?
Did you get the medicine?
응, 구했어
Yeah. I... I got it.
가서 얘기 좀 해
Come on. Let's go talk.
옥타비아, 저쪽에 있어
제발 뒤로 물러나
Octavia, just stay
there. Please, stay back.
그만둬
Stop.
아톰
Atom.
- 나도 어쩔 수 없었어
- 하지 마
There's nothing I could do.
Don't.
- 제발
- 하지 마
- Oh, oh, please.
- Don't.
- 잃은 사람은?
- 없어
Lose anyone here?
No.
제스퍼는?
Jasper?
여전히 숨을 쉬어
간신히
Still breathing. Barely.
걔를 제거할려고 했는데
네 사이코 여동생이...
I tried to take him out, but
your psycho little sister...
- 벨라미...
- 내 뭐? 내 뭐!
- Bellamy...
- My what? My what?
네 여동생
Your little sister.
그래야지
내 여동생
Yeah, that's right. My little sister.
내 여동생에 대해
할 말 더 있어?
Got anything else you
want to say about her?
없어
Nothing.
미안
Sorry.
밖으로 내다 놔
Get him out of here.
안녕, 여보
Hey, baby.
사람들에게
경고해야 돼, 애비
You have to warn them, Abby.
제이크, 그만해
Oh, Jake, stop.
Ark는 죽어가고 있어
뾰족한 수가 없어
Oh, the Ark's dying. There's no choice.
아니, 있어
Yes, there is.
지구가 있잖아
There's Earth.
적어도 우린
기회가 있을 거야
We'll at least have a chance.
여기, 꽉 붙잡고 있어
Here. Hang on to that.
그리고 이건 클라크에게
주면서 말해...
And... give this to Clarke
and tell her that I...
아빠!
Clarke: Dad!
넌 여기에 오면 안 돼, 아가
Clarke, you shouldn't be here, honey.
보고 싶지 않을 거야
You don't want to see this.
괜찮네
It's ok.
[Crying]
괜찮아
It's ok. It's ok.
자, 잘 간직해
Here. Keep that for me.
제이크, 때가 됐네
Jake, it's time.
[Kiss]
사랑한다
I love you, kid.
저도요
I love you.
Ok.
하느님 맙소사
Oh, my God. [Crying]
정말 죄송해요
I'm so sorry.
아가, 네 잘못이 아냐
Sweetheart, it's not your fault.
[Swallows]
아톰 일은 정말 미안해
I'm really sorry about Atom.
우린 여기서 사람들이
죽어가는 게 익숙해지려고 하잖아
I guess we're gonna have to get used to
people dying down here, aren't we?
근데 넌 아냐
내 말 들려?
But not you. You hear me?
넌 죽을 순 없어
You're not allowed to die.
웰스?
Clarke: Wells?
내가 그럴만한 가치가
없다는 거 알지만
I know I probably don't deserve it,
난 진실을 알고 싶어
but I need to know the truth.
내 엄마가 그랬지
맞지?
It was my mom. Wasn't it?
네 아빠에게 말한 게
엄마였어
She's the one who told your dad.
난 믿고 싶지 않았어...
I didn't want to believe it. I...
할 수가 없었어
I couldn't.
아빠가 죽어서
너를 탓했어
I blamed you because my father's dead
내 엄마의 실수였지
and it's my mother's fault.
그렇지?
Isn't it?
웰스...
제발
Wells... Please.
네가 어떤 심정인지 알아
I knew how you would feel.
- 널 보호하고...
- 싶었지
I wanted to... to protect me.
그래서 널 증오하게 했잖아
So, you let me hate you.
친구 좋다는 게 뭐야?
What are friends for?
어떻게 하면
날 용서해줄 수 있니?
How can you forgive me?
이미 용서했어
This is already done.
[Crying]
매끄럽네
Smooth. [Coughing]
구역질나네
맘에 들어
[Swallows] Disgusting. Love it.
나도...한 모금만 줄래?
Can I, uh, get a hit of that?
제스퍼!
Jasper!
좀 부드럽게 시작하자고
Let's start with the soft stuff.
잘 돌아왔어, 친구
Welcome back, buddy.
그게 꿈이였어 아님
내가 창에 맞은 거야?
Was that a dream or did I get speared?
그걸 증명할려면
인상적인 상처가 있어야지
You'll have a very
impressive scar to prove it.
내 구세주
My savior.
안 죽어줘서 고마워
Thank you for not dying.
오늘 약을 바를 거란
생각 못 했어
I don't think I could've taken that today.
내일도 안 죽도록
해봐야지
I'll try not to die tomorrow, too,
그게 좋다면야
if that's cool.
오, 안녕
Oh, hello.
[Crickets chirping]
안녕
Hi.
잠이 안 와?
Couldn't sleep?
잘 수가 없어요
I never can.
불침번이에요?
You on watch?
앉아
Join me.
저 악몽을 꿔요
I had a nightmare.
Hmm.
매일 밤 꿔요
I... I have them every night.
근데...악몽을 멈출
방법을 찾았어요
But... I think I found
a way to make them stop.
미안해요
I'm sorry.
안 돼!
No! [Groaning]
[Coughing]
[Choking]
매일 밤
그 아저씨가 보여요
Every night, I see him.
오빠 아빠요
Your father.
내 부모님을 죽이고
그 아저씨 얼굴이 보여요
He kills my parents
and... and I see his face
깨고 나면
오빠 아빠가 보여요
and... and I wake up and I see yours.
악몽은 절대 끝나지 않아요
And the nightmare never ends.
유일하게 끝낼 방법은...
The only way to make it end was...
악령들을 죽이는 거예요
was to slay my demons.
죽여야 했어요
I had to.
[Humming]